孩子们 我跟你们说过
Kids, have I ever told you
我是如何遇见你们老爸的吗
the story of how I met your father?
我就快进一下
Well, I'll just skip ahead
快进到我告诉他我怀孕的时候
to the moment I told him I was pregnant.
怎...怎么啦
W... What happened?
我晕过去了吗
Did I pass out?
不全是
Not exactly.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
你确定你不是长胖了
Are you sure you're not just getting fat?
哦 对
Oh, yeah.
这么说 你怀孕了
So, um, you're pregnant.
是的
Yeah.
哈
Huh.
看来你的咪咪还不知道啊（怀孕后乳房会变大）
Looks like nobody told your boobs.
怎么了
What happened?
我昏过去了吗
Did I pass out?
噢 我的
Oh, my...
求求你别打我
Please stop hitting me!
嘿
Hey.
你... 你确定你...
Are... Are you sure you're...
没有 不确定
Well, no, not positive.
大姨妈晚了一周了
I'm a week late.
可我从来都不晚 这可是我引以为傲的事
But I'm never late; it's a point of pride with me.
我准备下周一
I'm going to go
去看医生来确认下
see the doctor on Monday to find out for sure.
在那之前 你不许跟任何人讲
Until then, not a word of this to anyone.
连凯文也不说吗
Not even Kevin?
我觉得 孩子可能是他的
I mean, it's probably his.
我花费了数年的时间
I've spent years training my boys
来训练我的小蝌蚪朝相反的方向游
to swim the other way.
凯文和我还没做过
Kevin and I haven't had sex yet.
如果我怀孕了 你是孩子的父亲
If I'm pregnant, you're the dad.
那太棒了
That's wonderful!
啥
Huh?
我要当爸爸了
I'm gonna be a daddy!
HIMYM字幕组
翻译：加菲猪 Mr.Gao Roy.No2 安达小充 邵小庚 Henry
校对：园丁姐姐 47.4 Andie
本集之后进入冬歇 下一集2012年1月10日播映
好了 一杯威士忌是给我的
Okay, one scotch for me,
一杯加冰的冰茶给孩儿他妈
one iced tea on the rocks glass for Mommy.
闭嘴
Stop it.
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
我保密
Keeping it secret.
不好 我好像把我的给你了
Oop, I think I gave you the wrong one.
来 给我
Here, let me just...
赶紧把它交给我 放手
Give it to me. Drop... let go.
给哥放手
Take it away from you.
巴尼 为什么怀孕这事让你那么高兴
Barney, why are you so happy about this?
因为这好极了
Because this is perfect.
我想当爸爸
I want to be a dad.
这可不是好消息
This is not good news.
我有男朋友了
I have a boyfriend.
是啊 如果凯文不在的话
Yeah, but if Kevin weren't around...
不是这个问题
It doesn't matter!
我不想要孩子
I don't want kids.
我从来都不想要孩子
I've never wanted kids,
以后也不会 在未来的一百万年里 我也想不要孩子
and never, in a million years, will I ever want kids.
孩子们 对不住哈
Sorry, kids.
我不想要孩子
I can't have a baby.
嗨  朋友们
Hey, guys!
猜猜这是什么
Guess what this is!
你的袜子 靠 你真是个巨人
One of your socks? Boom! You're huge.
不 是我还未出生儿子的圣诞袜
No, it's our unborn son's Christmas stocking.
冈德森祖母在我和莉莉结婚的那天
Grandma Gunderson started knitting it
就开始织这只袜子了
the day Lily and I got married.
可是在她织完之前 她就去世了
She died before she could finish.
我真怀念圣诞袜
I miss stockings.
我继父克林特让我们扔掉所有的
My stepdad Clint made us get rid of anything
能让他觉得圣诞节商业化的东西
that reminds him of the commercialization of Christmas.
我记得你说过他扮成圣诞老人的事儿
I thought you said he dresses up as Santa.
是啊 呃 那是为了抗议性别定势
Yeah, but, uh, to protest gender stereotypes,
他扮成了圣诞老娘
he plays Santa as a woman.
尽管如此 圣诞老娘还留着大胡子
Though, he keeps the beard.
结果非常令人纠结
The result is disturbing.
我们要走了
Well, we should go.
我们得去爱婴园
We have to get to We B Babies
为我们的送礼会登记下(为新娘或即将分娩的妇女等举行的送礼会）
so that we can register for our shower.
我去不了
No can do.
我还得做个大项目
Um, I have a big project that I'm working on.
这是东梅多地区理查德・霍德曼的房子
This is Richard Holdman's house in East Meadow.
去年 他的圣诞装饰
Last year, he had the most visited Christmas display
是三州地区最受欢迎的
in the tri-state area.
但是 不是今年哟 知道为啥吗
But not this year. You know why?
因为大软糖来了
Because Big Fudge has come to town,
而且带来了他的两个朋友
and he brought his two friends:
曼宁...斯迪姆柔勒
Mannim... Steamroller.
比赛开始
Game on.
你没事儿吧
Are you okay?
没事儿
Yeah.
只是
Uh, it's just, um...
我讨厌曼宁・斯迪姆柔勒（美国非常受欢迎的圣诞歌曲组合）
I hate Mannheim Steamroller.
就没有别人可以帮你了吗
Isn't there anyone else you can use?
拜托 除了他们 我还能找谁啊
Come on! Who am I gonna use if not the Steamroller?!
我不知道 AC/DC不行么（AC/DC是70年代的摇滚乐队）
I don't know. AC/DC?
AC/DC
Ac/dc?
罗宾 你有没有想过
Robin, do you have any idea
他们为什么叫曼宁 斯迪姆柔勒
why they call them Mannheim Steamroller?
因为他们牛逼 哄哄 而且那么喜庆
Because they rock... so hard, so festively,
以至于你脑子都热得
that steam comes out of your brain.
一边冒烟一边熔化了
As it melts.
这么说 我得一个人去爱婴园了
So I have to go to We B Babies by myself?
我和罗宾陪你去
Robin and I will go with you.
巴尼 我们来这儿干嘛
Barney, what are we doing here?
我想让你明白养小孩这事儿
I want to show you that having a kid
没什么好怕的
is nothing to be afraid of.
孩子们 别闹了
Kids. Stop.
好了 第一项
Okay, first on the registry:
咪咪霜
nipple butter.
额哦
Uh-oh.
当你给小孩喂奶的时候
As you breast-feed,
你的乳头会长长些 大概有10厘米哟
your nipples stretch out, like, four inches
然后变的很干还会开裂
and get all dry and cracked.
乳头霜能遏制出血
The nipple butter stops the bleeding.
我十厘米长乳头会开裂而且会流血啊
My four-inch nipples are going to crack and bleed?!
对 但是当宝宝在吸你流血的乳头时
Yes, but while the baby is gnawing on your bleeding nips,
看看他会穿着什么小衣服哟
look what she'll be wearing.
疯狂的杜安
Insane Duane?
巴尼
Barney?
疯狂的杜安曾经是你们爸爸最好的朋友
Insane Duane was your father's best friend,
回到他认识我和你泰德叔叔之前
back in the days before he met me or your Uncle Ted.
我们准备去她住的地方了
We're going back to her place.
嘣
Boom!
好吧 你赢了
All right, you win!
这是二十块钱 是你只用一个字就勾到MM的
Here's 20 for picking up a girl with only one word.
这是另外的二十块钱 因为那个词是“错误”
And here's another 20 for that word being "Boner."
谢谢
Thank you.
一个小时以后 我和那个那个谁办完事后就来找你
I'll meet you back here in an hour when I'm done with, uh...
额 谁会在乎她的名字是什么
Ah, who cares what her name is;
她不会待太久 所以名字什么的无所谓啦
she won't be around long enough for it to matter.
好样的
Nice!
嘘
Shh...
我好久都没见到你了
I can't believe I haven't seen you around.
额 我和谢拉很快办完事之后
Well, after Sheila and I had that quickie,
我就忙着等孩子们出生 上幼儿园还有拉大便之类的事情了
my life's been playdates, preschools and poops.
我已经有几年都没踏进过酒吧的大门了
I haven't set foot in a bar in years.
你不喝酒了吗
You stopped drinking?
哦 我还在喝
Oh, I still drink.
阴道麻木喷雾
Vaginal numbing spray.
显然 生完孩子后
Apparently, after child birth,
你的“妹妹”就会变得像拳王洛奇的脸
your hoo-ha looks like Rocky Balboa's face.
-你不能生孩子  -我不能生孩子
- You can't have a baby! - I can't have a baby!
第二天 我们去看医生了
The next day, we went to the doctor.
好了 舍巴斯基女士
Well, Mrs. Scherbatsky,
我确定你和你的丈夫
I'm sure that you and your husband...
额 他不是我丈夫
Uh, he's not my husband.
噢 对不起
Oh, I'm so sorry.
你的男朋友
Your boyfriend then.
他不是我男朋友
He's not my boyfriend.
哦 额滴神
Oh, bozhe.
好吧   我就直奔主题了
All right, well, I will just cut to the chase.
等一下
Wait! Wait.
好了
All right.
好
Okay.
好了 我们准备好了 很好
All right, we're ready. Good.
你没有怀孕
You are not pregnant.
耶
Yeah!
-噢 耶   -耶
- Oh, yeah!   - Yeah!
这就是我想说的
That's what I'm talking about!
耶 你懂的 你懂的
Yeah, you know, you know!
再次对不起 孩子们
Again,sorry kids.
你好 先生
Hey, mister.
你要把这些圣诞灯挂起来么
Are you putting up all these Christmas lights?
哦 孩子 在我完工后
Oh, kid, by the time I'm done,
你可以从外太空看到这堆东西哟
you're gonna be able to see this son of a bitch from outer space.
哇 不错
Ah, cool.
我想把这些灯都挂在房子上
I wanted to put lights on our house,
可我爸爸说他太忙了
but my dad says he's too busy with work and stuff.
嘿 你看这样吧 你下个周末
Hey, what do you say, uh, you come back here next weekend
愿意来给我帮忙吗
and help me out?
耶
Yeah!
就这么说定啦
You've got yourself a deal.
我是史考特
I'm Scott.
我是 艾瑞克森先生
I'm... Mr. Eriksen.
谢谢 埃先生
Thanks, Mr. E.
埃先生
Mr. E.
就像一些小流氓刚刚拥有
Looks like some little scamp just earned the right
把维京人队的头盔戴到耶稣婴儿头上的权利一样
to put the Vikings helmet on baby Jesus.
那周以后 当我在享受
Later that week, as I was enjoying every second
没有怀孕的每一秒的时候
of not being pregnant...
接下来的青少年母亲
Next on Teenage Mommies...
你不是说过你会照顾贝拉吗
But you said you would watch Bella.
我得带啦啦队训练啊
I have cheerleading practice.
你真惨 布雷斯
Sucks to be you, Braces.
哦 额
Oh. Um...
哟呼
Yello!
额 好 我可以回来
Uh, yeah, I can come back in.
罗宾 我们上周做了一些检查
Robin, we ran some tests last week.
这事有些不太容易接受
This is going to be difficult to hear.
然后这医生说了一大堆医学上的东西
And then the doctor said a bunch of medical stuff that...
好了 重点是
well, the gist of it was this.
我不能生孩子
I can't have a baby.
是的 你不能生孩子了
No. You can't have a baby.
呃 太好了
Uh, great.
呃 我的意思是 也没那么好
Uh, well, I mean, um, not-not great.
我的意思是 我从来不想要孩子
I mean, I've never wanted kids,
所以要是发生在别人身上的 也没那么好
so if it has to happen to someone...
罗宾 你有可以倾诉这件事的对象吗
Robin, is there anyone you can talk to about this?
也许一个好朋友
Perhaps a close friend?
我知道我可以告诉我的朋友们
I knew I could have talked to my friends.
但是 只是我已经知道
But, it's just, I already knew
他们每个人会有什么样的反应了
exactly how they would all react.
泰德会努力让我感觉好点 却会做有点过头
Ted would go into overdrive trying to make me feel better.
你得吃点好吃的
You need comfort food.
炸鸡 芝士通心粉 土豆泥
Fried chicken, mac and cheese, mashed potatoes.
开礼物吧 我来帮你揉揉肩
Open your present, I'll work on these shoulders.
行了 深呼吸 放轻松 吃炸鸡
Okay, just breathe, relax, eat your chicken.
快点 吃啊 深呼吸
Come on, eat, breathe,
快打开 深呼吸 快打开 快点吃
open it, breathe, open it, eat.
罗宾 你为神马会绷得那么紧
Robin, why are you so tense?!
莉莉则会彻底崩溃
Lily would just implode.
我居然还一直在谈宝宝的事
And here I've been going on and on about babies.
喔 我真是一个不称职的朋友
Oh, I am such a bad friend!
到头来 还得我去安抚她
And I'd wind up comforting her.
安啦安啦
It's okay.
你应该朝着我的脸上来一拳
You have to punch me in the face!
马修则会问我一堆一堆的
Marshall would ask me a ton of questions
连我都不知该怎么回答的问题
I don't know the answers to.
-你又没有想过领养 -唔 我还
- Have you thought about adoption? - Um, well...
你家能接受这事吗
Does this kind of thing run in your family?
这个…
Uh...
你上次来大姨妈的时间 长度
What was the date, duration
还有稳定性如何
and consistency of your last period?
然后你的老爹将会鞠躬尽瘁地
And your father would bend over backwards
试着让我笑出来
trying to make me laugh.
一个基督教牧师和一个犹太教祭司一起走进了一家酒吧
A priest and a rabbi walk into a bar--
啊不 是理发店 啊不 是家邮局
no, a barbershop-- no, a post office--
啊不对不对 是两个牧师 啊还是不对 是两只鸭子
no, it's two priests-- no, it's two ducks--
记错了 是一个牧师手里拿着只鸭子 他是波兰人
no, a priest holding a duck-- and he's Polish.
是那个牧师 鸭子不是
The priest, not the duck.
实际上 那只鸭子也可以是波兰的哟
Actually, the duck could be Polish, too.
这点细节不要紧
Doesn't matter.
其实是还有问题的 那个鸭子不是波兰的
Yes it does. The duck's not Polish.
要是那样都没有用的话
And when that didn't work,
他也就真的 死而后已 了
he would actually bend over backwards.
平沙落雁
Pratfall!
嗷
Ow!
总之 我不想和他们说这事
The bottom line is, I didn't feel like talking about it.
所以当泰德问起来的时候
So when Ted asked...
嘿 罗宾 你没事吧 你好像不大开心啊
Hey, Robin, you okay? You look upset.
我就说了一个在第一时间跳到我脑子里的谎
I just came up with the first lie that popped into my head.
呃 没错
Yeah. Uh...
我刚刚得知我以后再也不能
I just found out I can never...
成为加拿大奥运队的撑杆跳选手了
be a pole-vaulter for the Canadian Olympic team.
或许是我太高了 或别的原因
I'm too tall or something.
罗宾 真抱歉 真的好可惜 罗宾
Robin, I'm sorry. I'm so sorry, Robin.
我无语了 这真是太糟了
I had no idea. That's terrible.
能不能给我们这里来份炸鸡啊 伙计
Can we get some fried chicken over here, stat!
我这个朋友实在是太不称职了
I am such a bad friend!
三个淫荡的修女出现在了圣彼得
Three slutty nuns show up at St. Peter's--
等等 她们不淫荡的
Wait, wait, they're not slutty.
唔 她们确实很淫荡 我提前剧透了
Well, they are, but you're not supposed to know that yet.
呃…
Um...
嘿 宝贝 怎么了
Hey, baby, what's up?
嘿 呃 听着
Hey, uh, listen, the construction of
建造霓虹交响曲的工时
the Symphony of Illumination is taking
要比预想的要长那么一点
a little longer than I thought.
好在我叫了史考特来帮我
Good thing I have Scott here to help me.
对不，史考特
Right, Scott?
当然啦 埃先生
You betcha, Mr. E!
坏消息
Bad news.
罗宾因为太高
Robin's too tall
而不能成为奥运会撑杆跳运动员了
to be an Olympic pole-vaulter.
问问她有没有填国际奥委会的上诉表格
Has she filed an appeal with the IOC?
你有没有填国际奥委会的上诉表格
Have you filed an appeal with the IOC?
问她能不能驼背让自个变矮点
Can she make herself shorter by slouching?
你能不能驼背让自个变矮点
Can you make yourself shorter by slouching?
问她有没有考虑过重新回学校
Has she considered going back to school
然后参加大学组的比赛
and competing at the collegiate level?
你有没有考虑过重新回学校然后
Have you considered going back to school and...
我不想讨论这件事
I don't want to talk about it.
抱歉
Sorry.
爱你呦 亲爱的 明天见了
I love you, baby. See you tomorrow.
好的 我也爱你
Okay, I love you, too.
史考特
Scott?
史考特 我的手机刚刚掉下去了
Scott, I dropped my phone.
对 我找着了
Yep, found it.
你能拿上来啊
Could you bring it up here?
好嘞
You got it.
嘿 我上来的时候 我能给你带瓶啤酒不
Hey, while I'm at it, can I get you a beer?
他想帮老头子带瓶啤酒
He wants to bring the old man a beer.
好啊 当然啦
Yeah, sure.
唔 冰箱里有一整箱呢
Uh, there's a whole case in the fridge.
谢了 儿子
Thanks, son.
你 你不介意我叫你儿子吧
Do you, do you mind if I call you "Son"?
随便你怎么叫我
You can call me whatever you want...
二货
jackass.
史考特
Scott?
梯子掉下去了
The ladder fell.
史考特
Scott?
Scott!
你在干嘛
What are we doing?
听着 唔
Listen, um,
我知道这几个星期以来
I know things have been kind of weird
我们之间有点怪异
between you and me these past couple weeks,
所以我只想说
so I just want to say I'm...
很高兴我们又回到了我们开始的地方
I'm glad we're back to where we started.
-嗯 -既是朋友又是炮友
- Yeah. - Friends with benefits.
-不 -一直不都是这样的吗
- No. - Just like always.
从来没有过 我们只是朋友
Never been that. Just friends.
加炮友 我们可以晚点再说
With benefits. We'll talk about it later.
看看这些小宝宝们啊
Look at all these babies.
你说这事疯不疯狂 因为我们没宝宝了
Isn't it crazy how, now that we're not having one,
他们又变得可爱了
babies are cute again?
看那个
Look at that one.
不用了
I'm good.
不 我说真的 看 看
No, I'm serious. Look, look.
该死
Damn it.
他像垃圾一样可爱
That thing's cute as crap.
去屎吧 小宝贝
Screw you, baby.
斯科特
Scott?
Scott!
怎么回事
What is going on?
-嘿 埃先生 -斯科特
-Hey, Mr. E. -Scott...
如果你不让我下去 我就要拼命乱叫
if you do not let me down, I am going to scream
直到有人来救我
my head off until someone comes to help me,
到时你就要和警察解释这些事了
and then you're going to have to explain all of this to the cops.
到时候你就要解释为什么
And then you'll have to explain why there's
你手机上会有我的小香肠的照片
a picture of my ding-dong on your phone.
我手机上没有
There is no picture of your...
现在有了哟
There is now.
哦 真是漂亮极了
Oh, yeah, that's a beauty.
斯科特
Scott?
Scott!
斯科特
马修一直要我
Marshall keeps
发些我咪咪的照片过去
asking me to text him pictures of my boobies.
过了这么多年
After all these years,
有时候他还是像个小青年
he sometimes still acts like a teenager.
一会回来
I'll be right back.
疯狂的杜安
Insane Duane.
现在是正常的杜安了
It's Sane Duane now.
你曾经那么赞啊
You used to be magnificent.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好 还好 我觉得
Yeah, yeah, um, I guess this, um,
撑杆跳这事 最终还是打击到我了
this pole-vaulting thing is finally hitting me.
我不明白 罗宾
I don't get it, Robin.
你真的想做撑杆跳选手吗
Did you really want to be a pole-vaulter?
不想 我 呃 我以前
No, no, I was, uh, I was always
非常不想拥有
adamantly against having a...
呃 撑杆跳生涯
uh, a pole-vaulting career,
虽然这是大部分女人都想要的
even though it's what most women want.
大部分女人想要当撑杆跳选手
Most women want to be a pole-vaulter?
在加拿大 在那边很火的
In Canada-- it's very big up there.
你懂的 认识一个不错的男人
You know, it's, it's meet a nice guy,
结婚 把杆撑起来
get married, vault some poles,
但我
but I...
一直不想那样
never wanted that.
当然 不想要是一回事
Of course, it's one thing not to want something.
不能要又是另一回事
It's another to be told you can't have it.
要是有一天你想法变了
I guess it's, it's just nice knowing
想要就能要该多好啊
that you could someday do it if you changed your mind.
但是现在 突然间 那个想法就破灭了
But now, all of a sudden, that door is closed.
试试一边滑雪一边射击怎么样?
What about the one where you ski and shoot at the same time?
你似乎很擅长那个哦
That seems like something you'd be good at.
噢天哪 罗宾 看这个
Oh, my God, Robin, look at this.
多么可爱的加拿大宝宝衣！
O Cana-dorable!
对吧
Am I right?
对不起
Excuse me.
哇哦 这个真好用
Yep, this works.
史考特
Scott,
等我下来之后
when I get down from here, you are going
你就有大麻烦了 小子
to be in big, big trouble, mister.
拜托 埃先生
Come on, Mr. E.
你年轻的时候难道没放纵过么
Didn't you ever cut loose when you were a kid?
那是两码事
That's irrelevant.
我是说 我当然放纵过
I mean, of course I did.
有一回 我爸妈出城了
One time, when my parents were out of town,
我和我兄弟把地窖烧了
my brothers and I set the basement on fire
办了个业余摔跤表演赛
hosting an amateur wrestling exhibition.
还有些戏剧效果在里面
There were some theatrics.
看 你懂我的意思
See, you get me.
我不觉得你像某些被我困在屋顶的呆瓜
I don't think of you as some dummy I trapped on the roof.
我觉得你更像 我的父亲
I think of you more like, like my dad.
我们的派对能再开半小时么
Can we keep the party going for 30 more minutes, please?
好吧 斯科特
Okay, Scott.
多谢 哥们
Thanks, Pop.
没关系 孩子们只是需要发泄一下
It's fine, kid just needed to blow off some steam.
不
No!
那可是冈德森奶奶织的
Grandma Gunderson knitted that!
史考特
Scott...!
这太疯狂了
That was crazy.
她哭着跑出去了
She just ran out of there crying.
现在连电话也不接
Now she's not answering her phone.
这几周她真的很奇怪
She's been acting really weird for a few weeks now,
从我们讨论飓风那天晚上开始
really since the night we discussed the hurricane.
巴尼 你们一起搭车回家的
Barney, you split a cab home.
她说了些什么吗
Did she say anything?
我们没怎么聊
We didn't really talk much.
好吧 幸运的是
Well, lucky for us,
这里有人非常擅长
someone at this table is skilled
侦查的艺术哟
in the art of detection.
罗宾不开心
Robin's upset.
她和凯文有问题了
She and Kevin are having trouble.
-他背叛了她  -不可能
- He cheated on her. -No way.
凯文是个诚实正派的人 他没那么幸运
Kevin's an honest, decent guy who never on his best day
可以勾搭上一个比罗宾更辣的美女
could pull a hotter chick than Robin.
那也许是罗宾背叛了他
Maybe Robin cheated on him.
也许罗宾才是跟别人上床的贱人
Maybe Robin is the dirty bird who slept with someone else.
我不知道 撑杆跳这事
I don't know, this pole-vaulting thing seems
感觉有点像灌篮啊
like a slam dunk to me.
噢 这太明显了
Oh, it is so obvious.
巴尼
Barney.
那个跟你一起工作的人
What is the name of that guy
叫什么名字 呃  兰迪
you worked with-- uh, Randy?
原来是跟兰迪
It was Randy.
等一下
Wait a second.
我已经破了这个案子了
I just cracked this case.
就是那个枫叶婴儿服
The little maple leaf onesie.
让她想家了
It made her homesick.
那到底是什么让她不开心呢
That's why she's so upset.
她不准备回家过圣诞
She's not going home for Christmas.
难道她想让我邀请她去我老家吗
She wants me to invite her to Ohio.
肯定是因为这个
That's got to be it!
或者是她又跟巴尼一起滚床单了
Either that or she slept with Barney.
噢 你肯定是史考特
Oh, you must be Scott.
喔 你好 太太
Oh, hello, ma'am.
见到您真荣幸
It's nice to finally see your face.
那么 我最好去啃书本了
Well, I'd better go hit those books.
年轻人 等一下
Hold it right there, young man.
这是一点心意 谢谢你帮了我老公
This is for helping out my husband.
哇噢 五十刀
Wow, 50 bucks.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
莉莉
Lily!
一张去克利夫兰的机票吗
An airplane ticket to Cleveland?
我知道这不是加拿大 但也相差不了多少(注:克利夫兰和加拿大首字母均为C)
I know it's not Canada, but it starts with a "C"
而且冷得都能缩成球了 赶紧打包吧
and it's cold as balls, so get packed.
你跟我一起回家过圣诞吧
You're coming home with me for Christmas.
老兄 想得美
Yeah, nice try, dude.
我可不会去六年来付了一亿二千五百万工资
I wouldn't go to Cleveland
给某人的克利夫兰
for $125 million paid over six years.
还继续啊
Still?
还要笑勒布朗吗（NBA球星 为拿总冠军离开克利夫兰队结果未能如愿 )
Still with the LeBron jokes?
那总冠军戒指到底在哪 啊
Where's that ring, huh?
那个本该拥有的戒指现在在哪
Where's that ring he's supposed to have by now?
听着 我只是 我觉得你不开心
Look, I just-- I thought you were bummed
因为你不能回家过圣诞
about not going home for Christmas.
你在开玩笑么
Are you kidding?
我喜欢在纽约过圣诞
I love New York at Christmas.
这里安静又祥和
It's so quiet and peaceful.
还有鸡蛋酒陪着我 所以
Got my eggnog to keep me company, so...
罗宾 怎么了
Robin, what's wrong?
没事 跟我说说吧
- Nothing. - Just tell me.
你怎么非想要知道啊
Why do you need to know so bad?
这样我好让你开心起来
So I can cheer you up.
让我开心这并不是你的工作
It's not your job to cheer me up.
是的 一直都是
Yes, it is.
让你开心是我的职责所在
Cheering you up is my job.
好吧 那你被炒了
Well, then, you're fired.
你不能开除我
You can't fire me.
我是工会的 贱人
I'm union, bitch.
这不是你该做的事
It's not your job to cheer me up.
-是的 本来就是   -这不是
- Yes, it is.   - No, it's not.
一直都是
Yes, it is.
一直都不是
No, it's not.
圣诞快乐 泰德
Merry Christmas, Ted.
圣诞快乐
Merry Christmas.
就这样 孩子们 最后我独自一人过了圣诞节
So, kids, I settled in for a Christmas alone.
我十分感激 泰德想要让我开心起来
I appreciated that Ted wanted to cheer me up,
不过说实话 其实没有必要
but honestly, it wasn't necessary.
所以我不能有自己的孩子
So I can't have kids.
非常大的代价
Big deal.
在这一刻 没有人能把我拉回生活的原路上去
This way there's no one to hold me back in life,
没有一个人能把我从游荡的途中拉回来
no one to keep me from traveling
当那时的我只想在街头游荡
where I want to travel,
没人能在我的职业生涯上碍事
no one getting in the way of my career.
如果你们想要知道真相的话
If you want to know the truth of it,
我很感激的是 你们并不是真实的
I'm glad you guys aren't real.
非常感激
Really glad.
靠
Damn it.
是的 这是我的工作
Yes, it is.
听着 如果你不想告诉我哪里出了岔子 也行
Look, you don't want to tell me what's wrong, fine.
我也没必要知道
I don't need to know.
但你不能阻止我逗你开心
But you can never stop me from trying to cheer you up.
这就是生活
It's a fact of life.
你只能学着去接受它
You're just gonna have to deal with it.
泰德
Ted...
等等 这可是最精彩的地方
Hold on, hold on, this is the best part.
我在通往地狱的高速公路上
I'm on the highway to hell
孩子们 罗宾阿姨没能成为一个撑竿跳选手
Kids, your Aunt Robin never became a pole-vaulter,
但是她却成为了一个有名的记者
but she did become a famous journalist,
一个成功的生意人 以及一个周游世界的旅行者
a successful businesswoman, a world traveler.
她还当过一阵子的斗牛士
She was even briefly a bullfighter--
这是个有趣的故事 以后我会慢慢讲给你们听
that's a funny story, I'll get to that one later.
但是有一样东西 你们的罗宾阿姨从来没有缺少过
But there's one thing your Aunt Robin never was.
她从来就不是一个人
She was never alone.
【HIMYM】字幕组倾情奉献